<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Leightcap</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack Leightcap</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 19:10:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Post Template</title>
      <link>/posts/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 19:10:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/template/</guid>
      <description>Syntax Highlighting Blocked, {{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;gt;}}CODE{{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}} With line numbers, 1 2 3  {{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;#34;linenos = table&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}}CODE{{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}}   Syntax highlighting a code block including the curly brace pairs is tough. No joke, my solution is to put a 😂 between the curly braces, which is invisible in the syntax highlighting ({😂{&amp;lt; ... &amp;gt;}😂}). I tried zero-width spaces and escape characters, but this huge bodge is a great functional use of emoji.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erik Satie - Vexations (1894)</title>
      <link>/projects/vexations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 15:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vexations/</guid>
      <description>First recording, 6 hours (2017) During my Junior year of high school, I recorded a 6-hour performance of Erik Satie&amp;rsquo;s Vexations.   This was extremely underplanned, and a surprising amount went wrong. I used Windows 10&amp;rsquo;s default camera app with a random webcam, and found - during the recording - Windows Camera had a 2 hour recording limit. Because I was recording audio separately, the audio and video were desynced, so the required merging of the video and audio required some guesswork in matching my fingers to the audio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlie &#39;the Traveling Salesman&#39; on the MBTA</title>
      <link>/projects/mbtaspeedrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 12:15:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mbtaspeedrun/</guid>
      <description>Using a brute force Traveling Salesman search of the MBTA Green Line, I found the shortest possible route which visits all 64 stops. The ideal time was about 3 hours. In practice, my best time is 3:15.   The search involved reducing the graph to a 6-node non-directed graph search. All paths start and end at the most extreme ends, Lechmere and Riverside respectively. Directionality was determined based on MBTA early morning time tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/readme/</guid>
      <description>Resume TeX Resume as of second semester of freshman year.
Packages dependencies: enumitem, geometry, graphbox, hyperref
Todo: * Other than gettings resume-worthy experience, * Declutter Education section * Use true \section*()s, rather than brute forced text headings * Fix Relevant Courses overfull \hbox size guessing * Make true adjustable parameters for sizes and number of items for scalability</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>