<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Leightcap</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack Leightcap</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 6 - Conclusion</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge6/</guid>
      <description>This final post is going to cover my general experience abroad, and recommendations both specifically for Cambridge and this program as well in general for a study abroad.
Cambridge and the PKP Pembroke-King&#39;s Programme As a bit of a reiteration of my first post, this study abroad was through the Pembroke-King&#39;s Programme, a six-week program(mme) that runs from early July into mid-August. At least for Northeastern, this runs about halfway through summer break until about a week or two before the start of the fall semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 5 - A Day</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge5/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m going to take you through a day here at Cambridge! I&#39;ve picked a day where I was ahead on work, so hopefully this is more interesting than &amp;ldquo;I&#39;ve spent the entire day in the library.&amp;rdquo;
8am - 1pm: Trip into London, Tate Modern I got up early to take the train into London - I&#39;m still impressed by the public transportation throughout the UK. People that spent more than a certain amount on a ticket for this train into London were refunded because the train was 10 minutes late - that&#39;s in stark contrast to the MBTA where you should consider yourself lucky if your train shows up within the hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 4 - Classes</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge4/</guid>
      <description>Background I&#39;m taking two classes while I&#39;m at Cambridge - History of the Modern Middle East and Shakespearean Drama. There were some more &amp;lsquo;traditionally&amp;rsquo; STEM classes available, but these two classes at least cover my last two humanities requirements at Northeastern. I definitely enjoy humanities classes I take, and I think it&#39;s important to find a balance in what you learn, but it&#39;s definitely a factor for me that these classes compress my humanities requirements into a 6 week period rather than taking up two classes in a ~15 week semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 3 - Concerts</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge3/</guid>
      <description>If you know me, then you know I like classical music to the point where it&#39;s almost concerning. So, a fair amount of my evenings here in the UK have unsurprisingly been hanging out with old people listening to classical music.
Because these concerts have been at night, my pictures have been pretty bad. So this post is going to be pretty scant on pictures, sorry.
Cambridge Summer Music Festival Bach - St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 2 - Museums</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge2/</guid>
      <description>Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology One of the handful of museums within a 5 minute walk of Pembroke College, the Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology&#39;s most interesting exhibit was about the local area. I&#39;d never bothered to look up why, but the College/University system at Cambridge is really distinct from the American system where &amp;ldquo;College&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;University&amp;rdquo; are used almost interchangeably (&amp;ldquo;Boston College&amp;rdquo; lying to you twice is a good example of the distinction).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Week 1 - Introduction</title>
      <link>/posts/cambridge1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cambridge1/</guid>
      <description>Background Before even going into my first year at Northeastern, I wanted to do a study abroad during my first summer. The timing is perfect, all my future summers at Northeastern will be mostly filled with co-op or engineering classes. Throughout the entire search for a study abroad program, my focus was on having the classes I would take count for as much as possible.\
During my second semester, I was deciding between programs at Oxford and Cambridge, but decided on the Pembroke-Kings Programme (PKP) at Cambridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Post Template</title>
      <link>/posts/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/template/</guid>
      <description>Syntax Highlighting Blocked, {😂{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;gt;}😂} CODE {😂{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}😂} With line numbers, 1 2 3  {😂{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;#34;linenos = table&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}😂} CODE {😂{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}😂}   Syntax highlighting a code block including the curly brace pairs is tough. No joke, my solution is to put a 😂 between the curly braces, which is invisible in the syntax highlighting ({😂{&amp;lt; ... &amp;gt;}😂}). I tried zero-width spaces and escape characters, but this huge bodge is a great functional use of emoji.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erik Satie - Vexations (1894)</title>
      <link>/projects/vexations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 15:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vexations/</guid>
      <description>First recording, 6 hours (2017) During my Junior year of high school, I recorded a 6-hour performance of Erik Satie&#39;s Vexations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlie &#39;the Traveling Salesman&#39; on the MBTA</title>
      <link>/projects/mbtaspeedrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 12:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mbtaspeedrun/</guid>
      <description>Using a brute force Traveling Salesman search of the MBTA Green Line, I found the shortest possible route which visits all 64 stops. The ideal time was about 3 hours. In practice, my best time is 3:15.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>