<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Jack Leightcap</title>
		<link>/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Jack Leightcap</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Cambridge Week 2 - Museums</title>
			<link>/posts/cambridge2/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/cambridge2/</guid>
			<description>Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology One of the handful of museums within a 5 minute walk of Pembroke College, the Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology&amp;rsquo;s most interesting exhibit was about the local area. I&amp;rsquo;d never bothered to look up why, but the College/University system at Cambridge is really distinct from the American system where &amp;ldquo;College&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;University&amp;rdquo; are used almost interchangeably (&amp;ldquo;Boston College&amp;rdquo; lying to you twice is a good example of the distinction).</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="museum-of-archaeology-and-anthropology">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology</h2>

<p>One of the handful of museums within a 5 minute walk of Pembroke College, the Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology&rsquo;s most interesting exhibit was about the local area.
I&rsquo;d never bothered to look up why, but the College/University system at Cambridge is really distinct from the American system where &ldquo;College&rdquo; and &ldquo;University&rdquo; are used almost interchangeably (&ldquo;Boston College&rdquo; lying to you twice is a good example of the distinction).
With objects from the founding of the early colleges at Cambridge, the exhibit mentioned the conflict between the scholars with royal protections and the locals causing the need for the castle-like colleges.
The colleges all have the layout of walled monasteries, with individual living spaces surrounding an open courtyard, a grand hall, a chapel, and a library to keep their knowledge safe.
This caries through to today, where I have to use a keycard to access the college past 7pm when the large, oak doors lock.</p>

<h2 id="the-fitzwilliam-museum">The Fitzwilliam Museum</h2>

<p>The Fitzwilliam Museum is eerily similar to the MFA.
There&rsquo;s the modernist sculpture on the lawns, the tacky gift shop and cafe, the pillars -  it all felt very familiar.
There are two special exhibits on display while I&rsquo;m here - the Beggarstaffs poster exhibition and an exhibition of paper fans.
Both exhibitions showed how a medium considered fairly mundane can be elevated to a fine art, and the fans were particularly interesting because of their connection to origami.</p>

<h2 id="sedgwick-museum-of-earth-sciences">Sedgwick Museum of Earth Sciences</h2>

<p>A very large building filled with many rocks. I had fun looking at rocks for about half an hour before I decided I had seen enough rocks.
There&rsquo;s a small room at the end of the long, main exhibition that focused on crystals.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/Museum1.jpg" alt="test" />
<center><strong><em>AP Chemistry memories</em></strong></center></p>

<p>The pretty colors and little models are much more my speed.</p>

<h2 id="scott-polar-research-institute-polar-museum">Scott Polar Research Institute (Polar Museum)</h2>

<p>This has been one of my favorite museums so far.
I walked by it on my way to my dorm on my first day here, not having heard of it before.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/Museum4.jpg" alt="test" />
<center><strong><em>One of the two entrance domes, with an antique map of each pole</em></strong></center></p>

<p>Half of the museum was a timeline of Arctic exploration, and the other half was a timeline of Antarctic exploration.
It took about 2 hours total to walk through both halves, and by the end of each half you really get a good sense of the characters and scale of both explorations.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/Museum3.jpg" alt="test" />
<center><strong><em>no booping was allowed</em></strong></center></p>

<p>I also really liked the memorial to sled dogs.</p>

<h2 id="cambridge-museum-of-technology">Cambridge Museum of Technology</h2>

<p>This was another museum that I just happened to stumble across.
The museum is a renovated decommissioned sewage pump station, and is a museum for just that.
It gives a history from early Cambridge when sewage was dumped into the River Cam to efforts to follow London in modernizing sewage treatment.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/Museum5.jpg" alt="test" /></p>

<p>The museum also includes a separate building dedicated to the history of manufacturing in Cambridge which reminded me of the history of Westinghouse.</p>

<h2 id="the-centre-for-computing-history">The Centre for Computing History</h2>

<p>This has definitely been my favorite museum I&rsquo;ve visited.
You first walk into the building and see the &ldquo;Megaprocessor&rdquo;, a microprocessor built to the scale of a large, hobbyist transistor.
Every logic gate is built from these large transistors, and these build up to the ALU, I/O, and all the way up to structured  Opcode and a playable game of Tetris.
This all includes extensive documentation, and I really could&rsquo;ve spent all day trying to map out each piece.
The creator is doing a Q/A at the museum later this month, and I definitely plan to visit at least a few more times.<br />
<br />
The next room has computers free to mess around on from the 1960s up to modern PCs. There was a book on BBC Micro programming, so of course I had to at least figure out
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-BASIC" data-lang="BASIC"><span class="lnt">1
</span><span class="lnt">2
</span><span class="lnt">3
</span><span class="lnt">4
</span><span class="lnt">5
</span><span class="lnt">6
</span><span class="lnt">7
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-BASIC" data-lang="BASIC"><span class="vg">I</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nl">1</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="w"></span><span class="kr">PRINT</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">FACTORIAL</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="vg">I</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="vg">I</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="vg">I</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="nl">1</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="w"></span><span class="kr">GOTO</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nl">2</span>
<span class="kr">END</span>
<span class="kr">DEF</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">FACTORIAL</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="vg">N</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="kr">IF</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">N</span><span class="o">&lt;=</span><span class="nl">1</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">THEN</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nl">1</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">ELSE</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="vg">N</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">x</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="vg">FACTORIAL</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="vg">N</span><span class="il">-1</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div></p>

<p>The last exhibit was focused on biographies of people involved in the computer revolution, with a focus on women that have been historically underrepresented in the history of computer science.
There&rsquo;s even a portrait of Zucc hanging ominously over you to really complete the experience.</p>

<h2 id="whipple-museum-of-the-history-of-science">Whipple Museum of the History of Science</h2>

<p>This museum has the interesting goal of documenting the historical aspect of science, which mostly focused on teaching aides and antique lab equipment.
It included an entire exhibit for globes, Darwin&rsquo;s microscopes, and even had number pseudo-scientific equipment on display, like a glorified Wheatstone bridge from the Church of Scientology that claims to measure thoughts.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/Museum2.jpg" alt="Atwood Machine" />
<center><strong><em>AP Physics memories</em></strong></center></p>

<p>It even included an early Atwood Machine, which if you&rsquo;ve ever learned about masses on a pulley or an expression like
<code>\[ \vec{a} = \frac{m_2 - m_1}{m_1 + m_2}\vec{g} \]</code>
then you&rsquo;ll appreciate this as much as I did.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Cambridge Week 1</title>
			<link>/posts/cambridge1/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/cambridge1/</guid>
			<description>Background Before even going into my first year at Northeastern, I wanted to do a study abroad during my first summer. The timing is perfect, all my future summers at Northeastern will be mostly filled with co-op or engineering classes. Throughout the entire search for a study abroad program, my focus was on having the classes I would take count for as much as possible.
During my second semester, I was deciding between programs at Oxford and Cambridge, but decided on the Pembroke-Kings Programme (PKP) at Cambridge.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Before even going into my first year at Northeastern, I wanted to do a study abroad during my first summer.
The timing is perfect, all my future summers at Northeastern will be mostly filled with co-op or engineering classes.
Throughout the entire search for a study abroad program, my focus was on having the classes I would take count for as much as possible.<br />
During my second semester, I was deciding between programs at Oxford and Cambridge, but decided on the Pembroke-Kings Programme (PKP) at Cambridge.
I&rsquo;m taking two classes (half a semester), <em>History of the Modern Middle East</em> and <em>Shakespearean Drama</em>, which fill my last two humanities requirements at Northeastern. I&rsquo;m going to make a whole post later in the program about these classes, and why I chose them.<br />
Without getting into the weird specific details of who I&rsquo;m paying for what and how much, my costs for this program are covered by my Dean&rsquo;s Scholarship and a GEO (Global Experience Office) Grant from Northeastern, and the YGL Scholarship from the Northeastern <a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/ygl/about-us/">Young Global Leaders</a>, an alumni group for &ldquo;the globalization of [Northeastern].&rdquo;</p>

<h2 id="getting-to-cambridge">Getting to Cambridge</h2>

<p>I flew from Newark to London Stansted with a layover in Copenhagen on SAS.
Getting a train from Stansted to Cambridge was extremely streamlined, it probably wasn&rsquo;t even necessary to buy my ticket in advance.
The public transportation around the entire area is fantastic, and in the future it&rsquo;s probably just as easy to fly to Heathrow or another larger airport and get to Cambridge.</p>

<h2 id="dorms">Dorms</h2>

<p>There are a couple different &lsquo;bands&rsquo; of housing available on the program.
The cheapest housing band was filled by the time I submitted my deposit, so I&rsquo;m in the second cheapest housing option, and a week into the program I&rsquo;m still genuinely shocked at how nice all of the rooms are.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/cambridge1-1.jpg" alt="Room1" />
<center><strong><em>Room in Pembroke College</em></strong></center></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m living at Pembroke College, in the dorm next to the Pembroke Chapel and across from the Pembroke Library.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/cambridge1-2.jpg" alt="Room2" />
<center><strong><em>View of Pembroke Library from my window</em></strong></center></p>

<h2 id="the-local-area">The Local Area</h2>

<p>Pembroke College is absolutely gorgeous.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/cambridge1-3.jpg" alt="Campus1" />
<center><strong><em>View of Old Court and the Porter&rsquo;s Lodge</em></strong></center></p>

<p>There are too many courts, lawns, orchards, and greens to take pictures of.
Unlike Northeastern where it&rsquo;s an advertising point to talk about &lsquo;hanging out on Centennial Common&rsquo; and the &lsquo;Urban Oasis&rsquo; of Boston, there is a <em>strict</em> policy of not stepping on the grass at Cambridge, to the point where there are signs everywhere, <em>in multiple languages</em>, telling people not to step on the grass.<br />
<br />
<img src="/post-images/cambridge/cambridge1-4.jpg" alt="Campus2" />
<center><strong><em>View of dorm, Pembroke Chappel, and Pembroke Library from the Library Lawn</em></strong></center></p>

<p>I really wanted to include a picture of the gigantic hall where we eat, but pictures aren&rsquo;t allowed while students are eating and it&rsquo;s locked otherwise. There are &lsquo;official&rsquo; pictures of the Formal Halls sent later, so I&rsquo;ll include those pictures when I get them.</p>

<h2 id="cambridge-the-city">Cambridge (the city)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent a lot of my time so far just wandering around Cambridge, and in a lot of ways it really reminds me of downtown Boston.
Old North Church surrounded by huge glass buildings is similar to churches from the 1300s next door to a Caffè Nero or Pizza Hut.
Being a college town, there&rsquo;s also the overwhelming amount of cafes and places to get coffee, to the point where I could probably get coffee from a different place every morning I&rsquo;m here.
There&rsquo;s also the similar tiny streets and sidewalks flooded with tourists, which is something I didn&rsquo;t miss.
Even the Fitzwilliam Museum within view of Pembroke College really reminds me of the MFA, even down to the free admission and modern art on the lawn (although not as iconic as the baby heads).<br />
Speaking of museums, my next post will be about what museums I&rsquo;ve visited.
Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Hugo Post Template</title>
			<link>/posts/template/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/template/</guid>
			<description>Syntax Highlighting Blocked, {{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;gt;}} CODE {{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}} With line numbers, 1 2 3  {{&amp;lt; highlight LANGUAGE &amp;#34;linenos = table&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} CODE {{&amp;lt; / highlight &amp;gt;}}   Syntax highlighting a code block including the curly brace pairs is tough. No joke, my solution is to put a 😂 between the curly braces, which is invisible in the syntax highlighting ({😂{&amp;lt; ... &amp;gt;}😂}). I tried zero-width spaces and escape characters, but this huge bodge is a great functional use of emoji.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="syntax-highlighting">Syntax Highlighting</h2>

<p>Blocked,
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-Go" data-lang="Go"><span class="p">{{&lt;</span> <span class="nx">highlight</span> <span class="nx">LANGUAGE</span> <span class="p">&gt;}}</span>
<span class="nx">CODE</span>
<span class="p">{{&lt;</span> <span class="o">/</span> <span class="nx">highlight</span> <span class="p">&gt;}}</span></code></pre></div>
With line numbers,
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-Go" data-lang="Go"><span class="lnt">1
</span><span class="lnt">2
</span><span class="lnt">3
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-Go" data-lang="Go"><span class="p">{{&lt;</span> <span class="nx">highlight</span> <span class="nx">LANGUAGE</span> <span class="s">&#34;linenos = table&#34;</span> <span class="p">&gt;}}</span>
<span class="nx">CODE</span>
<span class="p">{{&lt;</span> <span class="o">/</span> <span class="nx">highlight</span> <span class="p">&gt;}}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div>
Syntax highlighting a code block including the curly brace pairs is tough. No joke, my solution is to put a 😂 between the curly braces, which is invisible in the syntax highlighting (<code>{😂{&lt; ... &gt;}😂}</code>). I tried zero-width spaces and escape characters, but this huge bodge is a great functional use of emoji. It&rsquo;s also a great chance to reflect your personality in a write-up with 💩, for example.</p>

<h2 id="links">Links</h2>

<p>Easy use of Markdown. To display a link, the plaintext in <code>*.md</code>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">[<span class="nt">Google</span>](<span class="na">https://www.google.com/</span>)</code></pre></div>
renders as<br />
<a href="https://www.google.com/">Google</a></p>

<h2 id="tex">TeX</h2>

<p>Add to <code>footer.html</code> which is loaded on every page,
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="nt">script</span> <span class="na">src</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;//yihui.name/js/math-code.js&#34;</span><span class="p">&gt;&lt;/</span><span class="nt">script</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="nt">script</span> <span class="na">async</span>
  <span class="na">src</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;//mathjax.rstudio.com/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-MML-AM_CHTML&#34;</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="p">&lt;/</span><span class="nt">script</span><span class="p">&gt;</span></code></pre></div>
This uses MathJax, but it might be worthwhile to swap to KaTeX for faster rendering.</p>

<h3 id="math-mode">Math Mode</h3>

<p>To display Math Mode TeX, the plaintext in <code>*.md</code></p>

<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-LaTeX" data-lang="LaTeX">`<span class="sb">\[</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\nabla</span><span class="nb">} </span><span class="nv">\cdot</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{E} </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="m">0</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="s">\]</span>`
`<span class="sb">\[</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\nabla</span><span class="nb">} </span><span class="nv">\cdot</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{B} </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="m">0</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="s">\]</span>`
`<span class="sb">\[</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\nabla</span><span class="nb">} </span><span class="nv">\times</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{E} </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\frac</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\partial</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{B}}{</span><span class="nv">\partial</span><span class="nb"> t} </span><span class="s">\]</span>`
`<span class="sb">\[</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\nabla</span><span class="nb">} </span><span class="nv">\times</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{B} </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\frac</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="m">1</span><span class="nb">}{c^</span><span class="m">2</span><span class="nb">} </span><span class="nv">\frac</span><span class="nb">{</span><span class="nv">\partial</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\vec</span><span class="nb">{E}}{</span><span class="nv">\partial</span><span class="nb"> t} </span><span class="s">\]</span>`</code></pre></div>

<p>renders as
<code>\[ \vec{\nabla} \cdot \vec{E} = 0 \]</code>
<code>\[ \vec{\nabla} \cdot \vec{B} = 0 \]</code>
<code>\[ \vec{\nabla} \times \vec{E} = - \frac{\partial \vec{B}}{\partial t} \]</code>
<code>\[ \vec{\nabla} \times \vec{B} = \frac{1}{c^2} \frac{\partial \vec{E}}{\partial t} \]</code></p>

<h3 id="in-line">In-Line</h3>

<p>To display in-line TeX, the plaintext in <code>*.md</code>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-TeX" data-lang="TeX">The equation for eigenvalues is `<span class="s">\(</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\det</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nv">\lambda</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\textbf</span><span class="nb">{I} </span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="nv">\textbf</span><span class="nb">{A}</span><span class="o">)</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb"> </span><span class="m">0</span><span class="s">\)</span>`, neat huh?</code></pre></div>
renders as<br />
The equation for eigenvalues is <code>\( \det(\lambda \textbf{I} - \textbf{A}) = 0\)</code>, neat huh?</p>

<h2 id="images">Images</h2>

<p>Images are accessed from the <code>./static/</code> directory.
It seems better organized to make a subdirectory with the title,
so in this case within <code>./static/post-images/template</code> is an image <code>EMWave.png</code>. GIFs use the same format, so equivalently use GIF <code>EMWave.gif</code>.
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">![<span class="nt">Image Text</span>](<span class="na">/post-images/template/EMWave.png</span>)</code></pre></div>
renders as
<img src="/post-images/template/EMWave.png" alt="Image Text" /></p>

<h3 id="image-backgrounds">Image Backgrounds</h3>

<p>Add to <a href="https://hugo-theme-hermit.netlify.com/posts/creating-a-new-theme/#front-matter">front matter</a> of <code>*.md</code>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">images:
  - /post-images/template/EMWave.png</code></pre></div>
This uses a local image, but equivalently replace with a URL.</p>

<h2 id="embedded-youtube-videos">Embedded YouTube videos</h2>

<p>For a YouTube video URL <a href="https://youtu.be/rB83DpBJQsE">https://youtu.be/rB83DpBJQsE</a>, use the video ID (rB83DpBJQsE) and youtube.com/embed to make an embedded YouTube player. If just using an iframe, the video looks fine on desktop, but exceeds the text for small widths. To fix this, the size of the embedded video changes. This uses CSS, so in <code>config.toml</code> add <code>customCSS = [&quot;css/videos.css&quot;]</code>, where the file <code>videos.css</code> contains
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-CSS" data-lang="CSS"><span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">video-container</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="k">position</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">relative</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">padding-bottom</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">56.25</span><span class="kt">%</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">padding-top</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">30</span><span class="kt">px</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">height</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">overflow</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">hidden</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">video-container</span> <span class="nt">iframe</span><span class="o">,</span>
<span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">video-container</span> <span class="nt">object</span><span class="o">,</span>
<span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">video-container</span> <span class="nt">embed</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="k">position</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">absolute</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">top</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">left</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">width</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">100</span><span class="kt">%</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="k">height</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">100</span><span class="kt">%</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span></code></pre></div>
This adds the CSS necessary, so
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-HTML" data-lang="HTML"><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="nt">div</span> <span class="na">class</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;video-container&#34;</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="nt">iframe</span> <span class="na">width</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;853&#34;</span> <span class="na">height</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;480&#34;</span> <span class="na">src</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rB83DpBJQsE&#34;</span>
  <span class="na">allow</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34;</span>
  <span class="na">frameborder</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#34;0&#34;</span>
  <span class="na">allowfullscreen</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="p">&lt;/</span><span class="nt">iframe</span><span class="p">&gt;</span>
<span class="p">&lt;/</span><span class="nt">div</span><span class="p">&gt;</span></code></pre></div>
renders as
<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rB83DpBJQsE"
  allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"
  frameborder="0"
  allowfullscreen>
</iframe>
</div></p>

<h2 id="emoji">Emoji</h2>

<p>Finally something important: <code>:EMOJI:</code>, <code>joy</code>=😂, <code>poop</code>=💩, etc.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
